# Zia -UI Haq PMI-ACP, CSM

Lahore, Pakistan | P: +92 331 4356169 | zainzia90@gmail.com

### Summary

I have 10 years of experience in implementation of Quality Assurance, Software Testing, Automation Testing and Deployment life cycle. I have hands on experience in requirement gathering and analysis, Test effort estimation, Test planning, Test Design Matrix, Test case development and execution, Reviews, Software Quality Audits, Tasks Allocation, Tracking and Reporting. Hands on experience in working on Sauce Labs that manages the Cross Browser Testing and can be embedded with Automation Frameworks. I had been managing QA environments through AWS. Strong mentoring skills, capable of leading and motivating individuals to maximize productivity, exceptional communicator focused on building strong relationships with peers and clients. Proactive, Efficient in multi-tasking and decision making, known for achieving best quality and on time delivery. Highly motivated individual with excellent management, Leadership and analytical skills and Responsible individual who believes in continuous improvements.

#### Certification

- ❖ PMI-ACP® in 2020
- Certified ScrumMaster® in 2022
- Certified Agile Tester in 2019
- ❖ ISTQB Foundation Level certified in 2015

## **Professional Experience**

1. Strategic Systems International

**Designation:** Principal Software Quality Assurance Engineer

**Duration:** August 2019 – Present

2. NetSol Technologies Lahore

**Designation:** Principal Software Quality Assurance Engineer

**Duration:** September 2017 – August 2019

3. Strategic Systems International

**Designation:** Senior Software Quality Assurance Engineer

**Duration:** March 2016 – August 2017

4. NetSol Technologies Lahore

**Designation:** Senior Software Quality Assurance Engineer

**Duration:** March 2011 – March 2016

### **Education**

BS (Hons.) Computer Science 2006 - 2010

PUCIT, Lahore Pakistan

#### Skills

SQA

Jira

Test Management

CMMI Documentation

CMMI Audits

SQL

Sauce Labs

Team Server Foundation

Project Plan

Test Plan

Postman

Jenkins

Bloomrpc

GIT

JMeter

• Katalon

Selenium

API Testing

Trainings

Appium